ogone.com 2019-12-25

# Ingenico Group - INGENICO External Privacy Policy

## 1\. Privacy Policy

1.1. Ingenico Group S.A., its affiliates and subsidiaries, (together **INGENICO, we/us/our** ) are committed to safeguarding the privacy of our customers and users (you/your) who interact with INGENICO. You may give us information about you by filling in forms on our website (the Website) or by corresponding with us by letter, phone, e-mail or otherwise. This external privacy policy (the Privacy Policy) sets out our personal information collection and sharing practices and is intended to inform you of the ways in which we collect personal information, the uses of that personal information and the ways in which we will share any personal information you choose to provide to us.

1.2. If you are an existing customer of ours, further details about how we use your personal information is set out in your customer contract with us.  Further notices highlighting certain uses we wish to make of your personal information together with the ability to opt in or out of selected uses may also be provided when we collect personal information from you.

1.3. The Website may contain links to other third party websites (for instance, for registration purpose to events organized by third parties).  If you follow a link to any of those third party websites, please note that they have their own privacy policies and that we do not accept any responsibility or liability for their policies or processing of your personal information.  Please check these policies before you submit any personal information to such third party websites.  

1.4. This Privacy Policy is intended to explain our privacy practices and covers the following areas:

(a) What personal information about you we may collect;

(b) How we may use your personal information;

(c) How we protect your personal information;

(d) Contacting us & your rights to prevent marketing and to access and update your personal information;

(e) Our Cookies Policy;

(f) How changes to this Privacy Policy and the Cookies Policy will be made.

## 2\. Information we may collect about you

We will collect and process all or some of the following personal information about you:

  * **Information you provide to us  **personal information that you provide to us such as when you complete a form on our Website, including but not limited to, your name, email address, phone number, country and company (and/or the industry your work in). We may also process information on your education and work experience in connection with a job opening at INGENICO for which you wish to be considered. You may also provide us with your contact details, address and bank details to enable us to perform a contract you have entered into with us or to make payments to you in relation to goods or services you provide to us ;   
 
  * **Correspondence and other communications  **if you contact us by telephone, letter or by email, we will typically keep a record of that correspondence or communication;  
 
  * **Survey information and feedback  **we may also ask you to complete surveys that we use for research purposes or to provide feedback that we use to develop and improve our product and service offering.  In such circumstances we shall collect the information provided in the completed survey/feedback request;  
 
  * **Website and communication usage  **details of your visits to the websites and information collected through cookies and other tracking technologies including, but not limited to, your IP address and domain name, your browser version and operating system, browser language, access time, traffic data, location data, web logs, movements on the website, referring web site addresses and other communication data.  We may also collect information about the pages you view within the Website and other actions you take while visiting us. In addition, we may also use such technologies to determine whether you’ve opened an e-mail or clicked on a link contained in an e-mail.  
 
  * **Information from third parties  **we may also be provided with your information from other sources, for example from our affiliate companies or business partners in relation to business opportunities or from search engines, credit reference companies or government agencies, in relation to our due diligence processes.

## 3. Uses of your personal information

3.1. In this section, we set out the purposes for which we use personal information that we collect and hold and, in compliance with our obligations under European law, identify the “legal grounds” on which we rely to process the information.

3.2. These “legal grounds” are set out in European data protection law, which allows companies to process personal data only when the processing is permitted by the specific “legal grounds” set out in the law (the full description of each of these grounds can be found here)

3.3. Please note that, in addition to the disclosures we have identified below, we may disclose personal information for the purposes we explain in this notice to service providers, contractors, agents, advisors (e.g.  legal, financial, business or other advisors) and affiliates of INGENICO that perform activities on our behalf, as well as other members of the INGENICO group.

**(a) To communicate effectively with you and conduct our business, including to fulfil your requests  **to respond to your contact request, your registration request to events organized by INGENICO or your appointment request with one of our experts, to respond to your request for proposal or offer if you are interested in doing business with us or we may contact you if we are interested in doing business with you, to respond to your job application, to otherwise communicate with you and/or with other internal and external parties concerning you, or to carry out our obligations arising from any agreements entered into between you and us;  
_Use justification_ : contract performance, legitimate interests to enable us to perform our obligations and provide our services to you.  

**(b) To provide you with access to restricted Website areas  **to provide you with an online account and access to restricted areas such as the bank of images of the Group Media Library, where you have filled in a form to create an account on our Website.  
_Use justification_ : contract performance.  

**(c) To provide you with marketing materials  **to provide you with email alerts, updates, offers and invitations to INGENICO events, where you have chosen to receive these.  We may also use your information for marketing our own and our selected business partners’ products and services to you by [post, email, SMS, phone and fax] and, where required by law, we will ask for your consent at the time we collect your data to conduct any of these types of marketing.  We will provide an option to unsubscribe or opt-out of further communication on any electronic marketing communication sent to you or you may opt out by contacting us as set out in the “Contacting Us” section below.  
_Use justification_ : consent, legitimate interest to keep you updated with news in relation to our products and services.  

**(d) For research and development purposes  **to analyse your personal information in order to better understand your and our other clients’ services and marketing requirements, to better understand our business and develop our products and services;  
_Use justification_ : legitimate interests to allow us to improve our services.  

**(e) To personalize your experience on our Websites  **to collect statistics about our Websites’ usage and effectiveness through the use of various technologies, and personalize your experience while you are on our Websites, as well as tailor our interactions with you (see Section 6 below for further information).  
_Use justification_ : consent, legitimate interest to improve your user experience.  

**(f) To monitor certain activities  **to monitor queries and transactions to ensure service quality, compliance with procedures and to combat fraud;   
_Use justifications_ : legal obligations, legal claims, legitimate interests (to ensure that the quality and legality of our services.  

**(g) To inform you of changes  **to notify you about changes to our services and products;  
_Use justification_ : legitimate interests to notify you about changes to our service.  

**(h) To ensure Website content is relevant  **to ensure that content from our Websites is presented in the most effective manner for you and for your device, which may include passing your data to business partners, suppliers and/or service providers;   
_Use justification_ : legitimate interests (to allow us to provide you with the content and services on the Website.  

**(i) To reorganise or make changes to our business  **in the event that we: (i) are subject to negotiations for the sale of our business or part thereof to a third party; (ii) are sold to a third party; or (iii) undergo a re-organisation, we may need to transfer some or all of your personal information to the relevant third party (or its advisors) as part of any due diligence process for the purpose of analysing any proposed sale or re-organisation. We may also need to transfer your personal information to that re-organised entity or third party after the sale or reorganisation for them to use for the same purposes as set out in this policy  
_Use justification_ : legitimate interests in order to allow us to change our business.  

**(j) In connection with legal or regulatory obligations.  **We may process your personal information to comply with our regulatory requirements or dialogue with regulators as applicable, which may include disclosing your personal information to third parties, the court service and/or regulators or law enforcement agencies  in  connection  with  enquiries, proceedings or investigations by such parties anywhere in the world or where compelled to do so.  Where permitted and feasible, we will direct any such request to you or notify you before responding unless to do so would prejudice the prevention or detection of a crime.    
_Use justification_ : legal obligations, legal claims, legitimate interests to cooperate with law enforcement and regulatory authorities.

## 4\. Transmission, storage and security of your personal information

**Recipients**

4.1. In order to fulfil your requests, we may need to share or otherwise transfer your personal information within the INGENICO group such as to the INGENICO Sales, Communication or Marketing teams based in your country or relevant for your industry sector. Where appropriate we may also transfer your personal information to third parties, for example external event organizers or partner companies who may be in a better position to satisfy your request.

4.2. We may also share your personal information with our service providers who perform services on our behalf, for the purposes described in this Privacy Policy. We contractually require these service providers to use or disclose the personal information only as necessary to perform services on our behalf.

**Security over the internet  **

4.3. No data transmission over the Internet or website can be guaranteed to be secure from intrusion.  However, we maintain commercially reasonable physical, electronic and procedural safeguards to protect your personal information in accordance with data protection legislative requirements.

4.4. All information you provide to us is stored on our or our subcontractors’ secure servers and accessed and used subject to our security policies and standards.  Where we have given you (or where you have chosen) a password which enables you to access certain parts of our Websites, you are responsible for keeping this password confidential and for complying with any other security procedures that we notify you of.  We ask you not to share a password with anyone.

**Export outside the EEA  **

4.5. Your personal information may be accessed by staff or suppliers in, transferred to, and/or stored at, a destination outside the country in which you are located, whose data protection laws may be of a lower standard than those in your country.  We will, in all circumstances, safeguard personal information as set out in this Privacy Policy.  

4.6. Where we transfer personal information from inside the European Economic Area (the EEA) to outside the EEA, we may be required to take specific additional measures to safeguard the relevant personal information.  Certain countries outside the EEA have been approved by the European Commission as providing essentially equivalent protections to EEA data protection laws and therefore no additional safeguards are required to export personal information to these jurisdictions. In countries which have not had these approvals (see the full list here http://ec.europa.eu/justice/data-protection/international-transfers/adequacy/index_en.htm), we will establish legal grounds justifying such transfer, such as EU Commission-approved model contractual clauses, or other legal grounds permitted by applicable legal requirements.

4.7. Please [contact us](mailto:contact.dataprotection@ingenico.com?subject=Ingenico%20Privacy%20Policy) if you would like to see a copy of the specific safeguards applied to the export of your personal information. 

**Data retention**

4.8. Our retention periods for personal data are based on business needs and legal requirements. We retain personal data for as long as is necessary for the processing purpose(s) for which the information was collected, and any other permissible, related purpose. For example, we may retain the information you provided to us as long as necessary to provide you with the services you requested through our Website and until the time limit for claims which may arise from those services has expired, or to comply with regulatory requirements regarding the retention of such data. So if we use your personal information for more than one purpose we will retain it until the purpose with the latest period expires; but we will stop using it for the purpose(s) with a shorter period once that period expires.

4.9. When personal data is no longer needed, we either irreversibly anonymise the data (and we may further retain and use the anonymised information) or securely destroy the data. 

## 5\. Your rights & contacting us

**Marketing**

5.1. You have the right to ask us not to process your personal information for marketing purposes.  We will inform you if we intend to use your information for such purposes or if we intend to disclose your information to any third party for such purposes.  You can exercise your right to prevent such processing by not checking certain boxes in the forms we use to collect your personal information.  You can also exercise the right at any time by contacting us as set out in the “Contacting Us” section below.

**Updating information**

5.2. We will use reasonable endeavours to ensure that your personal information is accurate.  In order to assist us with this, you should notify us of any changes to the personal information that you have provided to us by contacting us as set out in the “Contacting Us” section below.  

**Your rights**

5.3. If you have any questions in relation to our use of your personal information, you should first contact our [Data Protection Officers](mailto:contact.dataprotection@ingenico.com%20?subject=Ingenico%20Privacy%20Policy).  Under certain conditions, you may have the right to require us to:

(a)    provide you with further details on the use we make of your information;

(b)    provide you with a copy of your personal information that we hold;

(c)    update any inaccuracies in the personal information we hold (please see paragraph 5.2);

(d)    delete any personal information that we no longer have a lawful ground to use;

(e)    where processing is based on consent, to withdraw your consent so that we stop that particular processing (see paragraph 5.1 for marketing);

(f)    object to any processing based on the legitimate interests ground unless our reasons for undertaking that processing outweigh any prejudice to your data protection rights; and

(g)    restrict how we use your information whilst a complaint is being investigated.

5.4. Please be aware that certain exceptions apply to the exercise of these rights and so you will not be able to exercise them in all situations. In addition, these will vary slightly between EU Member States. For instance, in France, in addition to the rights listed above, you also have the right to define directives as to how you wish your personal data to be used after your death. If you wish to exercise any of these rights we will check your entitlement and respond within the applicable timescale.

5.5. If you are not satisfied with our use of your personal information or our response to any exercise of these rights, you have the right to complain to the Supervisory Authority of your usual place of residence or place where the alleged breach to the law occurred. Please click here to see the list and contact information of the [EU Supervisory Authorities](http://ec.europa.eu/justice/data-protection/article-29/structure/data-protection-authorities/index_en.htm).

**Contacting us**

5.6. Depending on where you are located, the “data controller” of your personal information processed by us under this Privacy Policy will be different.  

5.7. If you have any questions in relation to this policy or want to exercise any of your subject rights described above, request, please contact our [Data Protection Officer](mailto:contact.dataprotection@ingenico.com?subject=Question%20about%20the%20Ingenico%20Privacy%20Policy).  

5.8. Please see here for a list of which group companies will be data controllers in which countries and obtain the contact details of the relevant Data Protection Officer.

## 6\. Cookies policy

6.1. We use cookies on the websites.  To find out more about how we use cookies, please see our Cookies Policy

## 7\. Changes to our Privacy Policy and/or Cookies Policy

7.1    We may change the content of our websites and how we use cookies and consequently our Privacy Policy and our Cookie Policy may change from time to time in the future.  If we change this Privacy Policy or our Cookies Policy, we will update the date it was last changed below.  If these changes are material, we will indicate this clearly on our Website.

7.2    This Privacy Policy was last updated on 23 May 2018.
